Register of the Vladimir Chelminski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Vladimir Chelminski papers
1894-2010
2002C91
Hoover Institution Archives
46 manuscript boxes (18.4 linear feet)
The Vladimir Chelminski papers contain extensive materials relating to economic and political conditions in Venezuela from the 1980s onward. The papers include many articles written by Chelminski for Venezuelan newspapers, as well as his book length study of price controls. There is also a detailed record of the workings of the Caracas Chamber of Commerce, including minutes of meetings and reports. Chelminski wrote summaries of many of his conversations with others on topics of economics and Venezuelan politics, which are found in the papers as well.
Chelminski, Vladimir.
Access
Boxes 44-45 closed until 2019 May 11. Box 46 closed until 2022 June 20.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
For twenty-four years, Vladimir Chelminski was the executive director of the Cámara de Comercio (Chamber of Commerce) in Caracas, Venezuela and an active participant in classical liberal circles around the country. He has written prolifically about economic conditions and political developments in Venezuela.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Vladimir Chelminski papers contain extensive materials relating to economic and political conditions in Venezuela from the 1980s onward. As the head of the Caracas Chamber of Commerce and as a prolific author of newspaper columns, Chelminski has been a strong advocate of free market policies and a critic of state regulation of the economy in Venezuela. He has opposed price controls, for example, and advocated the privatization of industry. His positions drew him into conflict with the government of Hugo Chávez, whose socialist policies were seen by Chelminski as leading to economic stagnation and the creation of a large state bureaucracy. The papers include many articles written by Chelminski for Venezuelan newspapers, as well as his book length study of price controls. There is also a detailed record of the workings of the Caracas Chamber of Commerce, including minutes of meetings and reports. Chelminski wrote summaries of many of his conversations with others on topics of economics and Venezuelan politics, which are found in the papers as well.
Laissez-faire.; Venezuela--Economic conditions.; Venezuela--Politics and government.; Venezuela--Social conditions.
- Biographical File, 1977-2005
  - Award, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings, 1989-2005 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Contents of binders containing biographical materials, 1977-2000
    - 1977-1985 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - 1999-2000 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Marriage license, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Travel diary, 1994 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Correspondence, 1986-2002
  - General, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Asman, David, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Chafuén, Alejandro, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Chelminski, Rudolph, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Childs, William, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Cisneros, Gustavo A., 2002 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Fernandez, Eduardo, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Futo, Gabor, 1991 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Helstrom III, Carl O., 1992 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Hinchberger, Bill, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Karabonev, A., 1995 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Lamo, Octavio de, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Langelfeld, James, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Lepp, Alan, 1986 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Mendez, Ramón, 1996 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Oberto G., Luis Enrique, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Peña, Alfredo, 1999 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Perez, Carlos Andrés, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Romero Nava, Edgar, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Sullivan, John D., 1992 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Ugalde, Luis, 1991 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Walker, Michael, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Weston, Bill, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 23)
- Speeches and Writings, 1983-2006
  - Letters to the editor, 1995-2004 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - "Bajos tributos suelen impulsar el desarrollo,", undated (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - "La reconstrucción...,", undated (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - "¿Hubo realmente liberación de precios?,", 1983 July-September (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - "El problema de los impuestos por ganancias de capital en Venezuela,", 1984 February 13 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - With Luis Enrique Otero, "Valores de Caracas,", 1984 October (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - "Economic Failure in Latin America and Prosperity in Asia,", 1986 (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - Summary of remarks, 1987 May 17 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - "Informe privatización,", 1988 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - "Perspectivas de la democracia venezolana,", 1988 February (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - "Venezuela: Coping with Controls,", 1988 April (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - "La falta de liquidez desangra la economía,", 1988 April 15 (Box-folder 3: 35)
  - "Carlos Andrés y Eduardo ante Fedecámaras,", 1988 July 3 (Box-folder 3: 36)
  - "El problema de la productividad,", 1988 November-December (Box-folder 3: 37)
  - "Carlos Andrés Pérez y los teléfonos,", 1988 November 7 (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - "Réquiem para los trabajadores,", 1988 November 16 (Box-folder 3: 39)
  - "Derechos humanos y las garantias economicas consagrada en la constitución venezolana,", 1988 November 18 (Box-folder 3: 40)
  - "Proyecto de Ley del Trabajo propende a disminución de la productividad,", 1988 December 30 (Box-folder 3: 41)
  - "Derechos humanos y las garantias económicas consagradas en la constitución venezolana,", 1989 (Box-folder 3: 42)
  - "Varios temas laborales,", 1989 (Box-folder 3: 43)
  - "Mayor desmpleo y menores remuneraciones,", 1989 January 22 (Box-folder 3: 44)
  - "Carlos Andrés Pérez,", 1989 January 28 (Box-folder 3: 45)
  - "Desmontemos los controles de precios ...si realmente queremos prosperar,", 1989 February 4 (Box-folder 3: 46)
  - "¿Empresario surgiendo ahorro obligatorio?,", 1989 April 4 (Box-folder 3: 47)
  - "¿Escandalosas o simplemente inexistentes?,", 1989 April 10 (Box-folder 3: 48)
  - "Mensaje para las nuevas generaciones,", 1989 June 8 (Box-folder 3: 49)
  - "Indexación de la nueva Ley del Trabajo es ruina para los trabajadores,", 1989 June 17 (Box-folder 3: 50)
  - "Recado para los niños de hoy,", 1989 July 1 (Box-folder 3: 51)
  - "La proposición sobre las prestaciones sociales,", 1989 November 22 (Box-folder 3: 52)
  - "Proposición sobre liquidar prestaciones beneficia a todos,", 1989 November 23 (Box-folder 3: 53)
  - "Empresas propiedad del Estado,", 1989 November 26 (Box-folder 3: 54)
  - "El lado bueno de la privatización y sus posibiliadades,", 1989 November 26 (Box-folder 3: 55)
  - "Aumentos de salarios, camino a mayor pobreza,", 1989 December 22 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - "Reflexiones sobre la proposición del cambio en las prestaciones,", 1990 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "Contra la proposición de los empresarios se han esgrimido argumentos producto de la reflexión,", 1990 January 11 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - "Opiniones sobre ventajas de los mercados libres,", 1990 September 19 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - "El Proyecto de Ley del Trabajo afectará a empresarios y trabajadores,", 1990 November 18 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - "La ley, la libertad y el débil,", 1990 November 22 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - "Los salarios pagan los impuestos a las empresas,", 1990 November 26 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - "¿Se justifica la lucha de clases?,", 1990 December 18 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - "Principales falacias que sustentan la Ley del Trabajo,", 1990 December 15 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - "Clases,", 1990 December 18 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - "Aumentos compulsivos de salarios, camino a mayor pobreza,", 1990 December 22 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Nueva Ley del Trabajo, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - "Breves comentarios sobre el indice de precios de la B.V.C.,", 1991 June 28 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - "Los encajes adicionales causan efectos perniciosos en la economía,", 1991 September 8 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - "Escasez de taxis,", 1991 September 8 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - "Similitudes entre el modelo comunista en Europa oriental y el populista latinoamericano,", 1991 September 28 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - "Razones para privatizar el Metro,", 1991 November 13 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - "Despilfarro en el Seguro Social,", 1991 November 19 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - "Privatizar para vivir mejor,", 1991 November 27 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - "¿Protección el Agro?,", 1991 December 12 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - "Razones para privatizar el petróleo,", 1991 December 24 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - "Principales razones del fracaso del Pacto Andino,", 1992 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - "¿Quienes piden la renuncia de CAP?,", 1992 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - "Solución para la crisis educativa venezolana,", 1992 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - "Salud-comparemosnos con Chile,", 1992 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - "Ley para promover y proteger el ejercicio de la libre competencia,", 1992 January 19 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - "Crisis fiscal, salud y educación,", 1992 January 23 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - "¿Por qué cambiar el regimen de pensiones?,", 1992 February 10 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - "Reflexión sobre la obra del gobierno,", 1992 February 17 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - "Cordiplan y el gasto del gobierno,", 1992 February 22 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - "Uslar, Caldera y CAP,", 1992 March (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - "La corrupción, de donde viene y adonde va,", 1992 March 5 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - "¿Corrupción?,", 1992 March 10 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - "El empresariado venezolano frente al Pacto Andino,", 1992 March 24 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - "Privatizar para vivir mejor,", 1992 Spring (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - "Buscando mayor Seguridad Social,", 1992 May 5 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - "¿Queremos majores pensiones y mejor salud?,", 1992 May 5 (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - "Soluciones a la crisis fiscal,", 1992 May 11 (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - "Venezuela, hacia una nueva constitución,", 1992 June 20 (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - "Aumentos compulsivos, caos para todos,", 1992 July-August (Box-folder 4: 40)
  - "Educación basica y media,", 1992 July 9 (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - "¿Más impuestos? Fallas en los argumentos del gobierno,", 1992 August 8 (Box-folder 4: 42)
  - "El futuro de los servicios públicos,", 1992 September 30 (Box-folder 4: 43)
  - "Estamos lejos de contar con un estado de derecho,", 1992 October (Box-folder 4: 44)
  - "Razones para limitar al estado,", 1992 October 4 (Box-folder 4: 45)
  - "Freedom of Contract Deserves More Respect,", 1992 October 13 (Box-folder 4: 46)
  - "El liberalismo y la Revolución Industrial,", 1992 October 28 (Box-folder 4: 47)
  - "El presupuesto si es reducible,", 1992 November 5 (Box-folder 4: 48)
  - "El Seguro Social y el bienestar de los trabajadores,", 1992 November 22 (Box-folder 4: 49)
  - "Los obispos y la problematica social,", 1993 April 20 (Box-folder 4: 50)
  - "La quiebra del Latino y el futuro del país,", 1994 March 28 (Box-folder 4: 51)
  - Conference presentation, 1994 May 23 (Box-folder 4: 52)
  - "Se buscan heroes que abran nuevos colegios,", 1993 July 23 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - "Apología del especulador y del afan de lucro,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - "Los empresarios de la educación requieren libertades para trabajar,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - "Matar la inflación de un solo golpe,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - "El populismo puede hundir aún más al consumidor,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - "¿Qué es lo que puede haber donde no hay justicia,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - "The Venezuelan Crisis Is not Due to Free Market Reforms,", 1994 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - "Un gobierno digno de estudio,", 1994 February 3 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - "En torno al IVA y a los controles de precios,", 1994 February 11 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - "El mito de la baja presión tributaria,", 1994 February 19 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - "Los debitos bancarios disminuiran los mercados de capitales,", 1994 March 19 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "Lecciones de la crisis bancaria venezolana,", 1994 March 20 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - "Inflación y burocracia,", 1994 May 11 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - "Cado vez habra menos autobuses,", 1994 May 14 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - "Controles de precios acabaran con los autobuses,", 1994 May 19 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - "El caso Aeropostal,", 1994 May 27 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - "Al gobierno le conviene combatir el contrabando,", 1994 May 30 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - "Carlos Andrés es inocente hasta aque se demuestro lo contrario,", 1994 June 23 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - "Ley de concesiones, un paso hacia adelante,", 1994 June 30 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - "Ataque contra especuladores traera más pobreza,", 1994 July 9 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - "Embestida contra la 'especulación' es una locura,", 1994 July 16 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - "Ataque contra el comercio es inmoral,", 1997 July 25 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - "Asambleas de padres, ocaso de la educación privada,", 1994 July 30 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - "La experienca boliviana tiene que ser estudiada,", 1994 August 19 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - "Buenas y malas leyes para defender al consumidor,", 1994 August 21 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - "¿Protoger o desprotoger al consumidor?,", 1994 September 11 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - "Esclavitud y consumo no son compatibles,", 1994 October 2 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - "Ganas de crear odios y de confundir,", 1994 October 17 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - "Tiempo de eliminar los controles sobre las divisas,", 1994 November 13 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - "Hechos que las autoridades no pueden ignorar,", 1995 January 20 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - "¿Leyes a favor o en contra del consumidor?,", 1994 November 30 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - "El problema moral se está agravando en Venezuela,", 1995 January 28 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - "Venezuela: Moralidad y comercio,", 1995 January 28 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Impuestos: Debemos ser más veraces y menos fiscalistas,", 1995 January 29 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - "Caja de Conversión,", 1995 March 26 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - "Ministro Cardenas, no destruya los colegios privados,", 1995 May 28 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - "Japón: lecciones para América Latina,", 1995 April 5 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - "La vía lógica de recabar impuestos,", 1995 June 18 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - "El verdadero desafío de Caracas,", 1995 August 27 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - "Medicamentos genéricos imposibles en Venezuela,", 1995 October 16 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - "Con bajos tributos el desarrollo es más viable,", 1995 December 4 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - "INDECU, balance ignominioso,", 1996 January 14 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - "Aumentando salarios minimos todos nos empobrecemos,", 1996 January 27 (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - "Gremios y estado contra farmacias, laboratorios y enfermos,", 1996 March 31 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - "Acabar con la inflación sin controles,", 1996 April 19 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - "Mejorar nuestra reputación y no olvidar al Consumidor,", 1996 April 22 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - "Tiempos de disminuir impuestos,", 1996 May 12 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - "¡Despierta Venezuela!,", 1996 June 9 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - "Venezuela necesita reformas más profundas,", 1996 June 14 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - "Promoción del robo y del caos,", 1996 July 8 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - "Convención de inversionistas,", 1996 July 10 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - "En Venezuela la reforma laboral parece imposible,", 1996 August (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - "Estancados por los impuestos,", 1996 September 1 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - "Cuba y AL: mentira oficial,", 1996 October 1 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - "¿Quiénes sobrevivirán: los contrabandistas o los comerciantes legitimos?,", 1996 October 14 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - "Breves consideraciones sobre los ajustes a los estados financieros por razones de inflación,", 1996 October 30 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - "La venta Cantv le abre rumbos al país," (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - "La creación de empleo debe ser la primera prioridad,", 1997 March 29 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - "Comercios de Caracas respaldan concesión,", 1997 May 15 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - "Los estragos de la inflación continúan,", 1997 June 1 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - "La mejor alternativa: ¡La autopista al litoral pro concesión!,", 1997 June 5 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - "Solidaridad: buena para unos pésima para otros,", 1997 November 2 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "Salarios mínimos, máximo problema,", 1997 December 28 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Los controles de precios: buenas intenciones y trágicos resultados
    - 1998 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - 2003 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - "Algunas ideas desordenadas sobre el caso venezolano,", 1998 March (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - "Control de alquileres, máxima injusticia social,", 1998 May 10 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - "¿Está Venezuela en venta?,", 1997 November 30 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - "Chavez's Tax Ideas Offer Venezuelans Little Comfort,", 1999 February 5 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - "Los impuestos asfixian a los venezolanos,", 1999 February 26 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - "La educación privada no aguanta más disaparates,", 1999 August 8 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - "Los derechos sociales seguirán siendo de papel,", 1999 October 10 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - "Prohibido privatizar,", 1999 October 31 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - "Contra todas las tendencias,", 1999 November 28 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - "Lo malo y lo peor de la Ley Orgánica de Hidrocarburos,", 2001 October (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - "Argentina quiebra y Venezuela sigue los pasos,", 2002 January 21 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - "Pdsva siempre estuvo llamada a paralizarse,", 2002 April (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - "El día que fallaron los medios,", 2002 May (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - "Sin rebaja de impuestos no habrá reactivación,", 2002 June (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - "Seguridad social,", 2002 August 4 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - "Los nuevos tributos agravarán la brecha fiscal,", 2002 August 26 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - "Venezuela: desempleo y proteccionismo,", 2002 August 26 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - "¿Proteccionismo para crear empleo?,", 2002 September 1 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - "Venezuela: ni un paso atrás,", 2003 January 15 (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - "Muere la economía y la libertad en Venezuela,", 2003 February 3 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - "Venezuela: controles fatales para la economía,", 2003 December 16 (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - "Oil Revenues Hit Chavez's Economic Ineptitude,", 2005 February 25 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - "Mitos sobre el latifundio,", 2005 December 19 (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - "¿Comercio entre iguales o entre desiguales?,", 2005 November 21 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - "Como el viaducto, el resto del país se extingue,", 2006 January 23 (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - "Conroles contraproducentes,", 2006 March 20 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - "Los roscas que todo lo encarecen,", 2006 April 7 (Box-folder 6: 37)
  - "Caracemos de razones para aleccionar al mundo,", 2006 May 22 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - "La explotacíon del hombre por el hombre,", 2006 June 19 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - "Controles de cambio: receta para el retraso,", 2006 July 17 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - "El control de precios todo lo destruye,", 2006 August 14 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - "Educacíon pública y privada,", 2006 September 11 (Box-folder 6: 42)
  - "Caracas trancada,", 2006 October 9 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - "¿Trabajaremos todos en la calle?,", 2006 November 6 (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - "Mitos sobre el libre comercio,", 2006 December 11 (Box-folder 6: 45)
- Notes on Readings and Miscellaneous Subjects, 1982-1994
  - Undated (Box-folder 7: 1-3)
  - 1982-1986 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - 1990-1991 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 7: 7)
- Cámara de Comercio de Caracas File, 1894-2004
  - Affidavit and credential, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Boletín, 1987-2004
    - 1987 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - 1990-1992 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - 1995-1997 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 2003 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 2004 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Budget, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Circulars, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 9: 8-10)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1999 (Box-folder 10: 1-9)
  - Declaration, 1991 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Historical file, 1894-1993 (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
  - Historical file, 1993 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Membership lists, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1982-1994 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
  - Press releases, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Proposals, 1989-2001 (Box-folder 11: 6-7)
  - Reports, 1974-1991 (Box-folder 12: 1-6)
- Office File, 1995-2007
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes articles, correspondence, memoranda, and reports.
  - 1995 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 13: 3-5)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
  - 1998 (Box-folder 14: 3-6)
  - 1998 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - 1999 (Box-folder 15: 2-5)
  - 2000 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - 2000 (Box-folder 16: 1-7)
  - 2000 (Box-folder 17: 1-4)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 17: 5-8)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 18: 1-8)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 19: 1-7)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - 2002 (Box-folder 20: 2-7)
  - 2002 (Box-folder 21: 1-7)
  - 2002 (Box-folder 22: 1-4)
  - 2003 (Box-folder 22: 5-7)
  - 2003 (Box-folder 23: 1-8, 24: 1-8, 25: 3)
  - 2004 (Box-folder 25: 4-7)
  - 2004 (Box-folder 26: 1-7)
  - 2004 (Box-folder 27: 1-6)
  - 2005 (Box-folder 27: 7-9)
  - 2005 (Box-folder 28: 1-8)
  - 2005 (Box-folder 29: 1-5)
  - 2006 (Box-folder 29: 6-9)
  - 2006 (Box-folder 30: 1-8)
  - 2006 (Box-folder 31: 1-6)
  - 2007 (Box-folder 31: 7-8)
- Subject File, 1943-2009
  - Bolivar, Simón, 1985 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Caldera, Rafael, 1993 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Center for International Private Enterprise, 1996-1999
    - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 32: 3)
    - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Chavez, Hugo, 2000 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Chile, 1973 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Cuba, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Iran, 1998 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Nicaragua, 1986 (Box-folder 32: 9)
  - Social security, 1991 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Venezuela, 1974-2001
    - Economic conditions, 1974-2001 (Box-folder 32: 11)
    - Education, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 32: 12)
    - Legal reforms, 1983-2007
      - 1983-1990 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - 1991-1995 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 33: 4)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 33: 5)
      - 2001-2002 (Box-folder 33: 6)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 33: 7-8)
      - 2007 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Newspapers, 1959-1987
      - 1959 (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - 1959-1987 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Petroleum industry, 1980 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - Politics and government, 1992-2006 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - Price controls, 1943-1998
      - 1943-1978 (Box-folder 34: 6)
      - 1971-1977 (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - 1981-1987 (Box-folder 35: 1)
      - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - Price indexes, 1950-1991 (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - Taxes, 1992-2009 (Box-folder 35: 4-6)
    - Taxes, 1992-2009 (Box-folder 36: 1-6)
  - World economy, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 36: 7)
- Writings by Others
  - Arcaya U., Pedro Manuel, 1991 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Bethell, Tom, 1987 (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - Blohm, Carlos Enrique, 1991 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Blohm, Henrik, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Blundell, John, 1989 (Box-folder 37: 5)